Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Aye, aye, Captain!
是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
Aye, aye, Captain!
是啊是啊，队长！
♪ Ooh!
♪ 哦！
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
♪ SpongeBob Squarepants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
♪ SpongeBob
Squarepants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤！ ♪
♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
♪ 如果是航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
♪ SpongeBob Squarepants! ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
♪ SpongeBob Squarepants!♪Ready?
♪ 海绵宝宝！♪ 准备好了吗？
♪ SpongeBob Squarepants!
♪ 海绵宝宝！
Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
字幕由 THE 赞助
美国教育部
and NICKELODEON
和尼克国际儿童频道
Oh, no, I lost my pen.
哦，不，我把笔丢了。
You can borrow mine.
你可以借我的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
I lost something once.
我有一次丢过东西。
I lost something
I couldn't live without...
我丢了东西
没有...我就活不下去
My identity.
我的身份。
So anyway, thanks for the pen.
无论如何，谢谢你的笔。
No problem, hon.
没问题，亲爱的。
It all started last week...
Monday morning to be exact...
一切都从上周开始……
确切地说是星期一早上...
The day I lost my identity.
我失去身份的那一天。
I got to go.
我得走了。
Good morning, world,
and all who inhabit it.
早上好，世界，
以及所有居住其中的人。
Awk! Gary, help! I can't see.
哎呀！加里，救命啊！我看不到。
Gary!
加里！
Gary, are you there?
加里，你在吗？
Gary? Gary, buddy?
加里？加里，伙计？
I need you to be my eyes, okay?
我需要你做我的眼睛，好吗？
Am I near the bathroom?
我靠近浴室吗？
Gary? Gary? Gar?
加里？加里？加尔？
Gary.
加里.
Now that my horrific
incident of terror is over
现在我的可怕的
恐怖事件已经结束
how 'bout some breakfast?
吃点早餐怎么样？
♪ The most important meal
of the day ♪
♪ 最重要的一餐
当日的♪
♪ Serving it up
Gary's way... pop! ♪
♪ 上菜
加里的方式...流行！ ♪
Enjoy, buddy.
享受吧，伙计。
Mmm. You know, I've been feeding
this to Gary for years
嗯。你知道吗，我一直在喂食
多年来这对加里来说
and I don't even know
what it tastes like.
我什至不知道
味道如何。
Bleah!
哎呀！
What is it, Peterson?
这是什么，彼得森？
I'm not sure.
我不知道。
I feel... a disturbance.
我感到……一种干扰。
That was the worst thing
I've ever tasted.
那是最糟糕的事情
我曾经尝过。
Oh, well, at least
I'll never have to do it again.
哦，好吧，至少
我再也不用这么做了。
Barnacles!
藤壶！
All these shenanigans
made me late for work.
所有这些恶作剧
让我上班迟到了。
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
All right.
好的。
Hi, SpongeBob.
嗨，海绵宝宝。
Hi, Patrick.
嗨，帕特里克。
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ La-la-la-la
la-la-la-la-lah ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦
啦啦啦啦啦♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la-lah
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ La-la-la-la
la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦
啦啦啦♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ La-la-la-la
la-la-la... ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦
啦啦啦……♪
Wait a minute.
等一下。
When exactly did you
lose your identity?
你具体什么时候
失去你的身份？
Yeah, and who's Patrick?
是啊，帕特里克是谁？
Why did you eat Snail-Po?
你为什么吃蜗牛宝？
Have patience, good people.
要有耐心，善良的人。
A great story can't be rushed.
一个伟大的故事不能操之过急。
However, I willskip ahead
to The Krusty Krab.
不过，我会跳过
到蟹堡王。
Order up!
赶快下单吧！
One Krabby Patty, grilled
with the fiery warmth
一份烤蟹肉饼
带着火热的温暖
of my beating heart. Enjoy.
我跳动的心。享受。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Uh...
呃...
Oh.
哦。
Is there a problem?
有问题吗？
Well, you really should
be wearing a name tag
嗯，你真的应该
佩戴名牌
so I can thank you properly.
这样我就可以好好地感谢你了。
While it is against
my philosophy
虽然是反对
我的哲学
to disagree with a customer
不同意顾客的意见
I must point out that I am,
in fact, wearing a name tag...
我必须指出，我是，
事实上，戴着名牌...
right here.
就在这里。
Huh?
啊？
Uh... SpongeBob.
呃……海绵宝宝。
Oh, Squidward, it's terrible.
哦，章鱼哥，太可怕了。
It's the most terrible thing
that's ever happened to me.
这是最可怕的事情
这曾经发生在我身上。
I lost my name tag.
我丢失了我的名牌。
Pourquoi?!
普尔奎伊？！
SpongeBob, take it easy.
海绵宝宝，放轻松。
I'm sure you can get a new one.
我确信你能得到一件新的。
But I don't want
a new one, Squidward.
但我不想
一个新的，章鱼哥。
My name tag is
out there somewhere.
我的名字标签是
就在外面的某个地方。
Lost... Hungry...
迷路了……饿了……
Who will help it?
谁来帮助它？
What if someone's using it?
如果有人使用怎么办？
All right, nobody move!
好了，没人动！
This is a bank robbery!
这是抢劫银行！
Attica!
阿提卡！
I'm innocent, I tell ya.
我是无辜的，我告诉你。
Wow... Ooh...
哇……哦……
Squidward, what happened?
章鱼哥，发生什么事了？
Huh? Oh, you fainted
啊？噢，你晕倒了
because you lost your
name tag or something.
因为你失去了你的
名字标签什么的。
Huh?
啊？
SpongeBob, will you get
ahold of yourself?
海绵宝宝，你会得到吗
坚持自己吗？
Since when is losing
your name tag
从什么时候开始失去
你的名字标签
the end of the world?
世界末日？
Attention, all employees!
全体员工注意了！
Just a quick heads-up, boys.
只是快速提醒一下，孩子们。
There's going to be
a surprise uniform inspection
将会有
突击统一检查
in one hour.
一小时内。
Anyone who doesn't pass,
gets the boot.
凡是没有通过的人，
获得引导。
This boot, to be exact.
确切地说，是这款靴子。
It's very stinky
非常臭
and you have to wear it all day.
而且你必须整天戴着它。
See you in an hour.
一小时后见。
SpongeBob, if you really want
海绵宝宝，如果你真的想要的话
to find your name tag,
just retrace your steps.
找到您的姓名标签，
只要原路返回即可。
Retrace my steps?
追寻我的足迹？
Squidward, you're a genius.
章鱼哥，你真是个天才。
Huh. Huh. A genius.
呵呵。呵呵。一个天才。
Well, I don't know
about that, but...
嗯，我不知道
关于那件事，但是……
Cover me till I get back, okay?
掩护我直到我回来，好吗？
Oh, sure, sure.
哦，当然，当然。
A genius. Well,
how about.... Hey!
一个天才。嗯，
怎么样……嘿！
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
If I'm going to retrace my steps
如果我要回溯我的脚步
I got to remember
everything I did this morning.
我必须记住
我今天早上所做的一切。
Hi, SpongeBob.
嗨，海绵宝宝。
Oh, hi, Patrick.
哦，嗨，帕特里克。
You said hi to me
this morning, right?
你向我打招呼
今天早上，对吗？
As I do every morning.
正如我每天早上所做的那样。
Well, I need you to do it again.
好吧，我需要你再做一次。
That wasn't part
of the deal, Squarepants.
那不是一部分
这笔交易，Squarepants。
Patrick, what are
you talking about?
帕特里克，什么是
你在说什么？
My hellos aren't just
some tape recording
我的问候不只是
一些磁带录音
that you can rewind
and play over and over.
你可以倒带
并一遍又一遍地玩。
They're special.
他们很特别。
Patrick, this is an emergency.
帕特里克，这是紧急情况。
I lost my name tag this morning
今天早上我丢失了名牌
and I need to retrace my steps.
我需要原路返回。
You lost your name tag?
你丢了名牌吗？
Okay, Patrick, you
know the plan, right?!
好吧，帕特里克，你
知道计划吧？！
I got it, I got it.
我明白了，我明白了。
You're going to retrace your
steps and when you walk by me
你将追溯你的
脚步以及当你走过我身边时
I say, "Hi,"
just like this morning.
我说：“嗨”
就像今天早上一样。
Perfect!
完美的！
Mm, I guess I should start
with when I woke up.
嗯，我想我应该开始了
当我醒来时。
I sure hope this works.
我当然希望这能起作用。
Good morning, world,
and all who inhabit it.
早上好，世界，
以及所有居住其中的人。
Awk!
哎呀！
So far, so good.
到目前为止，一切都很好。
I don't see my name tag up here.
我在这里没有看到我的名字标签。
Now that my horrific incident
of terror is over
现在我的可怕事件
恐怖已经结束
how 'bout some breakfast?
吃点早餐怎么样？
♪ The most important meal
of the day ♪
♪ 最重要的一餐
当日的♪
♪ Serving it up
Gary's way. ♪
♪ 上菜
加里的方式。 ♪
Bleah!
哎呀！
Okay. Next I just have
to walk outside
好的。接下来我只有
到外面走走
and say hi to Patrick.
并向帕特里克问好。
Patrick!
帕特里克！
What?
什么？
You were supposed
to say hi to me.
你本来应该
跟我打招呼。
Hi.
你好。
Oh. All right,
let's take it from the top.
哦。好吧，
让我们从上往下看。
Bye, SpongeBob.
再见，海绵宝宝。
Don't forget your
line this time!
别忘了你的
这次上线！
I won't.
我不会。
Good morning, world
and all who inhabit it.
早上好，世界
以及所有居住其中的人。
♪ The most important
meal of the day ♪
♪ 最重要的是
当天的一餐♪
♪ La-la-la, Gary's way
Bleah!
♪ 啦啦啦，加里的方式
哎呀！
Patrick, why
didn't you say hi to me?
帕特里克，为什么
你没跟我打招呼吗？
What's my motivation?
我的动机是什么？
Forget the motivation.
忘记动机。
Just say hi!
就打个招呼吧！
Hi, Patrick.
嗨，帕特里克。
Wait! I'm Patrick.
等待！我是帕特里克。
I'm sorry. Sorry.
对不起。对不起。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Let's try it again.
让我们再试一次。
Bleah!
哎呀！
Hi, SpongeBoob.
嗨，海绵宝宝。
SpongeBoob?!
海绵布布？！
I-I said... ha-ha!
我、我说……哈哈！
Who's SpongeBoob?
海绵宝宝是谁？
I said SpongeBoob!
我说的是海绵宝宝！
Again, again. Sorry, people.
再一次，再一次。对不起，各位。
♪ The most important
meal of the day ♪
♪ 最重要的是
当天的一餐♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, Gary's way.
Bleah!
♪ 是的，是的，加里的方式。
哎呀！
I got the giggles.
我笑了。
Oh, what's the use?
哦，那有什么用呢？
I'll never find my name tag
in time for inspection.
我永远找不到我的名字标签
及时进行检查。
Well, what did you do
嗯，你做了什么
after I said hi to
you this morning?
在我打招呼之后
今天早上你吗？
Hmm. Let's see.
唔。让我们来看看。
I skipped merrily
to The Krusty Krab.
我高兴地跳了起来
到蟹堡王。
Said hello to old man Jenkins.
向老詹金斯打招呼。
Hi, Mr. J.
你好，J 先生。
Placed an apple
on Mr. Krabs's desk
放了一个苹果
在蟹老板的桌子上
and that's about it.
就是这样。
Oh, and these two guys
threw me in the dumpster.
哦，还有这两个人
Yi-yi-yi.
依依依。
Good one, guys!
好啊，伙计们！
Whoa!
哇！
That's it!
就是这样！
Your name tag is in the apple
你的名字标签在苹果里
on Mr. Krabs' desk.
在蟹老板的桌子上。
Patrick, you're a genius.
帕特里克，你是个天才。
Oh, wait, he's probably
thrown it away by now.
哦，等等，他可能是
现在就把它扔掉了。
Well, then, we'll
look in the dumpster.
那么，我们就
看看垃圾箱。
What is that stench?
那是什么臭味？
That is the stench of discovery.
这就是发现的恶臭。
Come on, buddy, I'll
give you a boost.
来吧，伙计，我会
给你动力。
Hop on, pal.
上车吧，朋友。
Yup-ho!
是啊嗬！
Hey, it's not so bad,
once you get used to it.
嘿，事情没那么糟糕，
一旦你习惯了。
I wish I had a nose.
我希望我有一个鼻子。
Come on in, buddy,
the garbage is fine.
进来吧，伙计，
垃圾还好。
Cannonball!
炮弹！
You look over there
你看那边
and I'll look over here.
我会看看这里。
Okay.
好的。
Patrick.
帕特里克.
I'm looking, I'm looking.
我在找，我在找。
Patrick.
帕特里克.
Patrick!
帕特里克！
I'm looking as fast as I can.
我正在尽可能快地寻找。
Patrick!!
帕特里克！！
Thank you.
谢谢。
Here, let me get that.
在这里，让我明白这一点。
Hey, look... a
Stingray 5000 single.
嘿，看……一个
黄貂鱼 5000 单。
Hey, these guys rock!
嘿，这些家伙摇滚！
Why would anybody
throw this away?
为什么有人会
把这个扔掉吗？
Have you forgotten
what we're looking for
你忘记了吗
我们在寻找什么
knee deep in yesterday's
Top 40 songs?
昨天的膝盖深
前 40 首歌曲？
Yes.
是的。
I'll give you a hint:
Two words.
我给你一个提示：
两个字。
First word, "my."
第一个词是“我的”。
Second word, "name tag."
第二个词，“名牌”。
Could I have another hint?
我可以有另一个提示吗？
Patrick, I would love
to sit here
帕特里克，我会喜欢
坐在这里
and play "20 Questions" with you
和你一起玩“20个问题”
but I've only got
one minute till inspection.
但我只有
距离检查还有一分钟。
Aah! One minute?!
啊啊！一分钟？！
Hurry, Patrick!
快点，帕特里克！
We don't have much time.
我们没有太多时间。
Hey, SpongeBob.
嘿，海绵宝宝。
Not now, Patrick.
不是现在，帕特里克。
I know where your name tag is.
我知道你的名牌在哪里。
Where? Where?
在哪里？在哪里？
Uh...
呃...
I can't remember.
我不记得了。
Patrick, I don't
have time for this.
帕特里克，我不
有时间做这个。
There it is!
就在那里！
Where?!
在哪里？！
Uh. I forgot again.
呃。我又忘记了。
Patrick, are you with me
or against me?
帕特里克，你和我在一起吗
还是反对我？
Well, could you give me a hint?
嗯，你能给我一个提示吗？
There! I see it!
那里！我看到了！
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
The boy who cried, "Name tag."
是啊是啊……
那个男孩喊道：“名牌。”
If you're not going to help me
如果你不打算帮助我
then just go crawl
back under your rock.
然后就去爬行
回到你的岩石下面。
Well, at least I don't
wear my shirt backwards.
好吧，至少我不这么认为
把我的衬衫反穿。
My shirt backward? What the...?
我的衬衫反了？什么……？
My shirt's on backwards!
我的衬衫穿反了！
I had my identity all along.
我一直都有自己的身份。
Oh, and just in time.
哦，来得正是时候。
Thanks, Patrick.
谢谢，帕特里克。
Don't mention it, buddy.
别提了，伙计。
Fall in for inspection!
过来接受检查！
All right, you two.
好吧，你们两个。
Hat and uniform
seem to be in order.
帽子和制服
看起来很正常。
Hmm...
唔...
Promise me you'll shave
tonight and you pass.
答应我你会刮胡子
今晚你就过去了。
Hoo-rah.
呼啦。
Okay, boy, your turn.
好吧，孩子，轮到你了。
I think you'll find
everything ship-shape.
我想你会发现
一切都是船形的。
Jumping jellyfish,
what's that stench?
跳跃的水母，
那是什么臭味？
Uh, discovery?
呃，发现？
And that's how I got
my identity back.
这就是我得到的
我的身份回来了。
Welp, that's my story.
好吧，这就是我的故事。
Well, you managed
to kill 11 minutes.
好吧，你成功了
消磨11分钟。
Thanks, uh...
谢谢，呃...
Betty.
贝蒂。
What? Oh, sweetie,
I'm not Betty.
什么？哦，亲爱的，
我不是贝蒂。
I just borrowed her uniform
while mine's at the cleaners.
我刚借了她的制服
而我的则在清洁工那里。
Ah, The Krusty Krab
啊，蟹堡王
home of the delicious
Krabby Patty
美味之家
蟹肉饼
and its super-secret recipe.
以及它的超级秘密配方。
Attention, Krusty Krab crew!
蟹堡王工作人员请注意！
All hands report immediately!
全体人员立即报告！
Fry Cook SpongeBob
reporting, sir!
炒海绵宝宝厨师
报告，先生！
What's all the yelling about?
大家都在喊什么？
Today is the 25th anniversary
今天是25周年纪念日
of the first time
me archenemy Plankton
第一次
我的大敌浮游生物
ever tried to steal me secret
曾经试图窃取我的秘密
Krabby Patty formula.
蟹黄饼配方。
Can I have the secret formula?
可以给我秘方吗？
No! Okay.
不！好的。
But he was persistent.
但他很执着。
Pretty please? Uh-huh.
请问漂亮吗？嗯嗯。
He used disguise...
他用了伪装...
Super-science...
超科学...
civil disobedience...
公民不服从...
and I always came out on top.
我总是名列前茅。
Fascinating.
迷人。
But thousands of failures
have made him crafty
但数以千计的失败
使他变得狡猾
so keep your eyes open.
所以请睁大眼睛。
You never know
what trick he'll use
你永远不知道
他会用什么伎俩
to steal me secret
Krabby Patty formula.
偷我的秘密
蟹黄饼配方。
What a quaint restaurant.
多么古雅的餐厅啊。
I think I will sample
their wares.
我想我会采样
他们的商品。
Ooh, how weird...
哦，多么奇怪啊...
A machine made to
look like a customer.
一台机器被用来
看起来像一个顾客。
SpongeBob, why don't you go
hose out the men's room.
海绵宝宝你怎么还不走
用软管冲洗男厕所。
With pleasure, sir!
很高兴，先生！
I'lltake this one.
我要这个。
Welcome to The Krusty Krab, sir.
先生，欢迎来到蟹堡王。
May I help you?
我可以帮你吗？
Yes, please.
是的，请。
I'd like an order
of chili coral bits.
我想要一个订单
辣椒珊瑚块。
You sure you don't want
a Krabby Patty?
你确定你不想要
蟹肉饼？
No, thank you.
不，谢谢。
Will this cover it?
这个会覆盖吗？
Uh... sure.
呃...当然。
Here you go.
干得好。
Good day.
再会。
Hm. I was sure it was
one of Plankton's tricks.
嗯。我确定是
浮游生物的伎俩之一。
Well, at least his money's good.
好吧，至少他的钱还不错。
Aha!
啊哈！
Plankton! You knew I would
never distrust a dollar!
浮游生物！你知道我会
永远不要不相信一美元！
That's right, Krabs.
没错，蟹蟹。
Now, hand over the secret
Krabby Patty formula!
现在，交出秘密
蟹黄派配方！
Or what?
或者什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I never thought
I'd get this far.
我从没想过
我会走到这一步。
Well, then, allow me to
suggest your next move.
那么，请允许我
建议你的下一步行动。
Yowww!
哟哟！
Curse you, Krabs!
蟹蟹们，诅咒你们！
And now for the chaser.
现在是追逐者。
You just wait, Krabs!
蟹蟹们，你等着吧！
Next time I'll...
下次我会...
Who am I kidding?
我在跟谁开玩笑呢？
At least I can go home
to a wife who understands.
至少我可以回家
给一个能理解的妻子。
So, tell me what happened.
那么，告诉我发生了什么事。
I don't want to talk about it.
我不想谈论它。
Talking will make
you feel better.
说话会让
你感觉好多了。
Leave me alone.
请别打扰我。
That's your problem...
You never let anyone in.
那是你的问题...
你从来不让任何人进来。
Plankton the rock,
Plankton the loner.
浮游生物岩石，
浮游生物是孤独的。
And she's off,
ladies and gentlemen.
而她却下班了
女士们、先生们。
You have to do
everything yourself.
你必须做
一切都是你自己。
That's why everything you try
ends up like this.
这就是为什么你尝试的一切
最终是这样的。
And like this.
像这样。
And more recently, like this.
最近，就像这样。
I'm a failure!
我是个失败者！
It's not that bad.
没那么糟糕。
You just require a little help.
你只需要一点帮助。
Maybe some henchmen.
也许是一些追随者。
Henchmen?
追随者？
Yes. What you need to do
是的。你需要做什么
is surround yourself
with muscular tough guys
是围绕着你自己
和肌肉发达的硬汉们
who will do whatever you say.
谁会照你说的做。
I like the sound of that.
我喜欢那个声音。
I'll canvass all the seediest
lowbrow dives in town
我会调查所有最肮脏的
在城里低俗潜水
to find my minions.
去寻找我的爪牙。
And I know just how to speak
their language.
我知道如何说话
他们的语言。
Felicitations, malefactors!
恭喜你，恶人！
I am endeavoring
to misappropriate
我正在努力
挪用
the formulary
for the preparation
处方集
为准备
of affordable comestibles.
负担得起的食品。
Who will join me?!
谁来加入我？！
I don't get it...
No matter what I do
我不明白...
无论我做什么
I always end up being squashed
by someone bigger than me.
我总是被压扁
由比我大的人。
Oh, come on.
哦，来吧。
I think you're overreacting.
我认为你反应过度了。
Sorry.
对不起。
That's okay... I'm no different
没关系...我也不例外
than the millions
of other plankton in the sea.
比数百万
海洋中的其他浮游生物。
The plankton family
浮游生物家族
has always been pushed around
and stepped on.
一直被推来推去
并踩了上去。
Wait. That's it.
等待。就是这样。
Acting alone, we're powerless
单独行动，我们无能为力
but united, the plankton family
但团结起来，浮游生物家族
could be a real pain
in the belly!
可能会很痛苦
在肚子里！
Krabs may think one plankton
is no problem
螃蟹可能认为一种浮游生物
没问题
but let's see him take on two
但让我们看看他对阵两个
or ten
或十个
or 100
或 100
or 1,000!
或 1,000！
And why stop there?
为什么停在那里？
I'll gather every family member
from every corner of the ocean.
我会召集每一个家庭成员
来自海洋的每一个角落。
The entire plankton family
整个浮游生物家族
under one roof!
同一个屋檐下！
Krabs won't stand a chance
螃蟹没有机会
against the staggering intellect
对抗惊人的智力
of a million super-smart
criminal masterminds!
百万超级聪明人
犯罪主谋！
They're here!
他们来了！
Welcome, brethren!
欢迎弟兄们！
Hey, look here, buddy...
It's Cousin Plankton!
嘿，看这里，伙计...
这是浮游生物表弟！
Yee-haw!
呀呀！
I've been away from home
longer than I thought.
我已经离开家了
比我想象的要长。
Well, howdy, cousin!
嗯，你好，表弟！
Guh...
呃……
It's me, Clem.
是我，克莱姆。
Of course, you remember Zeke
当然，你还记得泽克
Rufus, Jete, Billy Bob,
Billy Jim
鲁弗斯、杰特、比利·鲍勃、
比利·吉姆
Billy Billy Bo Willy
Banana Fana Fo Filly
比利·比利·波·威利
香蕉法纳福母马
Doug, Enos...
道格、以诺斯……
Julio, Fletcher McGee,
Rainchild...
胡里奥、弗莱彻·麦基、
雨子...
All right, I get it!
好吧，我明白了！
I mean, uh, come inside,
make yourself at home.
我的意思是，呃，进来吧，
让自己宾至如归。
I'd like you to meet
my computer wife, Karen.
我想让你认识一下
我的电脑妻子凯伦。
Golly, she sure is
pretty, Sheldon.
天哪，她确实是
漂亮，谢尔顿。
Sheldon?
谢尔顿？
Yes, that's my first name.
是的，这是我的名字。
Sheldon?! Will you please...?
谢尔顿？！请你...?
I'm sorry. All right
对不起。好的
as I was saying...
正如我所说...
Okay, we all know
Sheldon's a funny name.
好吧，我们都知道
谢尔顿是一个有趣的名字。
O-ho-kay.
Okay, I'm done.
哦好的。
好吧，我完成了。
No more.Good.
没有了。很好。
To continue.
继续。
Only you can bring honor...
只有你才能带来荣誉……
And dignity...
还有尊严...
Back to the plankton...
回到浮游生物...
For years, it has been my goal
多年来，这一直是我的目标
to acquire
the secret formula for...
获得
秘密配方...
Okay, that's enough!
好吧，够了！
Sheldon! Ha...
谢尔顿！哈...
Bottom line:
we invade The Krusty Krab
底线：
我们入侵了蟹堡王
so I can steal
the secret formula.
这样我就可以偷东西
秘密公式。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Uh, what's in it for us?
呃，这对我们有什么好处？
Hey, what about us?!
嘿嘿，那我们呢？！
Well, what do you want?
嗯，你想要什么？
Garsh! Could I get
a new string for my banjo?
嘎什！我可以得到
我的班卓琴需要一根新弦吗？
And another boot
to match this 'un?
还有另一只靴子
匹配这个'un？
And some more memory
for my laptop?
还有一些记忆
对于我的笔记本电脑？
What about root beer?
根汁汽水怎么样？
Root beer?!
根汁汽水？！
Help me get the secret formula
帮我找到秘密配方
and you can have as much
root beer as you can drink.
你可以拥有尽可能多的
根汁汽水可以直接喝。
Victory, thy name is plankton!
胜利，你的名字是浮游生物！
Well, Mr. Squidward
好吧，章鱼哥先生
it's almost closing time,
and we haven't seen
快到关门时间了
我们还没有看到
eye or antenna
of old Plankton for hours.
眼睛或天线
老浮游生物几个小时。
Yes, sir, I think this time,
he's finally given up...
是的，先生，我想这一次，
他终于放弃了……
Attention,
Krusty Krab management.
注意，
蟹堡王管理。
This is your better speaking.
这是你更好的演讲。
What?!
什么？！
I have the restaurant
surrounded.
我有餐厅
包围。
Give me the secret formula
给我秘密配方
or I'll destroy The Krusty Krab.
不然我就毁掉蟹堡王。
Eh, you and what army, bug?
呃，你和什么军队，虫子？
What army?
什么军队？
What army?!
什么军队？！
Look around you, Krabs.
看看你的周围，蟹蟹们。
You planted grass?
你种草了吗？
Grass?!
草？！
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
You'll never get away with it,
Plankton!
你永远都逃脱不了它
浮游生物！
You're right...
the pipes are
much too narrow.
你是对的...
管道是
太窄了。
Besides, what I really want
is the Krabby Patty formula.
除此之外，我真正想要的是什么
是蟹黄派的配方。
Well, you might as well
forget it!
嗯，你也可以
算了！
The formula is locked away
in me safe
公式已被锁定
在我安全的情况下
and I'll never give you
the combination.
我永远不会给你
的组合。
Silence!
沉默！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
哇！哇！哇！哇！哇！
I think you'll find
we're more than capable
我想你会发现
我们有能力
of figuring it out
for ourselves.
弄清楚它
为了我们自己。
Oh, boys?
哦，男孩们？
That's it...
A little to the left.
就是这样...
向左一点。
Curse you plankton
诅咒你的浮游生物
and your ability
to join together
和你的能力
一起加入
to form a working human ear.
形成一个能工作的人耳。
Hot dog!
热狗！
Yes!
是的！
It's mine! The formula's mine!
这是我的！公式是我的！
After all these years,
it's finally mine!
这么多年过去了，
它终于是我的了！
Let it be known that on this day
让大家知道，在这一天
I, Sheldon J. Plankton
我，谢尔顿·J·浮游生物
single-handedly overthrew
The Krusty Krab!
一手推翻
蟹堡王！
Ahem!
咳咳！
A-And if course, I had
a little help from the family.
A-当然，我有
来自家人的一点帮助。
Plankton, wait!
You can't look
at the formula!
浮游生物，等等！
你不能看
在公式中！
Begging won't help.
乞讨是没有帮助的。
I'm telling you,
you won't be able
to handle the truth.
我告诉你，
你将无法
来处理真相。
There's some things
in this world
有一些事
在这个世界上
that weren't meant
for mortal eyes.
那不是这个意思
对于凡人的眼睛。
Eye.
眼睛。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
Drumroll, please!
请击鼓！
Finally, after all these years
终于，经过这么多年
I'm about to find out what makes
a Krabby Patty taste so good.
我正要找出是什么让
蟹肉饼味道真好。
The secret recipe
for one Krabby Patty is...
秘方
对于蟹比帕蒂来说...
"A pinch of salt..."
“少许盐……”
Plankton, wait!
浮游生物，等等！
"three teaspoons
of chopped onions..."
“三茶匙
切碎的洋葱……”
I'm warning you.
我警告你。
"a cup of love..."
“一杯爱……”
Don't do it!
不要这样做！
"mixed together
“混合在一起
"with the most important
ingredient of all...
“与最重要的
所有...的成分
"four heaping pounds
of freshly ground...
“四磅重
新鲜磨碎的...
plankton"?
浮游生物”？
I warned you.
我警告过你。
Hey, why ain't you running?
喂，你怎么不跑？
Well, I can't read.
嗯，我读不了。
Get out of here.
离开这里。
Hyuh, hyuh, hyuh, hyuh.
嘿嘿嘿嘿嘿
Hey, guys. Did
I miss anything?
嘿，伙计们。有吗
我错过了什么吗？
Mr. Krabs, is this really
the secret ingredient
蟹老板，这真的是吗？
秘密成分
for the Krabby Patty?
为了蟹肉饼？
Of course not.
当然不是。
And Plankton'll probably
figure that out
浮游生物可能会
弄清楚
and be back again to find out
what the real formula is.
再次回来看看
真正的公式是什么。
But don't worry, boys...
但别担心，孩子们……
The formula's safe from harm.
该配方不会受到伤害。
I got it hidden
in me most secret
hiding place...
我把它隐藏了
在我最秘密的地方
藏身之处...
A place no one,
not even Plankton,
would ever figure out.
无人的地方，
连浮游生物都没有，
永远会弄清楚。
Let me guess... it's at home
under your mattress.
让我猜猜...在家里
在你的床垫下。
Curse you, Squidward!
诅咒你，章鱼哥！
Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
字幕由 THE 赞助
美国教育部
and NICKELODEON
和尼克国际儿童频道
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
标题为
WGBH 媒体访问小组
访问.wgbh.org
标题为
WGBH 媒体访问小组
访问.wgbh.org